What? The fucking rudder of purple wing?
什么「紫翼之舵」啊
Do you flatter yourselves to be birds?
你以为你们这就成了鸟么
Both you and me
不论是我还是你们
is still a mole crawling underground!
不还是在地上爬来爬去的鼹鼠么
If you wanna leave the moles, come on seriously!
要是不想当鼹鼠了 就来正面上我啊
I'll take on you even with bare hands!
老子赤手空拳也不怕
αὔρα
αὔρα
What's the hell that aura is, feeling so bad.
这什么鬼 这个恶心的念纹…
Those who can do nothing without relying on somebody else,
不跟谁勾搭在一起就一事无成的家伙
go pray quietly and play the boating games!
还是老老实实回船上去祈祷玩过家家吧
Let's go back.
走 回去了
Yeah.
是呢
Shit.
该死
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Fallaina was the soul of the mud whale.
作为泥鲸之魂的法莱那
However that soul was not protecting us at all.
但它却并非是保护我们的存在
Instead, it took the lives of Shirushi and ate them.
而却吞噬「印」的生命 以之为食
sentikinesis
thymia
Those who with thymia, and those who without.
拥有情念力的人 和没有这个能力的人
It seems that
泥鲸那时
the mud whale was divided into two parts.
仿佛被掰断成了两截
The final section
最 终 节
It is great I was born here
最 终 节
Suo.
苏澳
Are you going to visit Masoo?
你们也是来探望玛索的吗？
We've digged some bamboo shoots.
我们去挖了竹笋
I wonder if he could get up today...
不知道今天能起来吗…
I hope so.
能起来就好了
Here you come.
请进
It's just like my parents.
果然 和我爸妈那时候一样
Their sleep time became longer and longer.
睡眠时间变得越来越长
And they lost their consciousness...
意识渐渐开始模糊…
Chakuro, are you OK?
查克罗 你没事吧？
Huh?
嗯？
You don't seem well today.
今天你一直无精打采的
I... I just had a sleepless night...
因…因为我没睡好…
Masuo?
玛索？
You sloth!
你这个懒虫
How long are you going to sleep!
打算睡到什么时候啊
I recalled something...
我回想起了…
No, many things...
各种各样的事情…
I thought everyday is the same,
本以为我们日复一日
we just repeating the same life.
重复着一模一样的生活
But everyday is different from each other.
但其实每一天都是不一样的
We knew we are the descendants of the sinners, and we fought.
我们知道了自己是罪人的后裔 开始了战斗…
Why we had to hurt others...
为什么我们不得不去伤害他人…
But you are not dirty.
但是记住 你们的双手并不肮脏
I was the only one bloody.
沾满鲜血的坏事
I will bring all the sins with me into the sea of sand.
都会随我一起葬身沙海…
So please live confidently, forever...
所以 不管在哪 都要挺起胸膛活下去
I will bring the pains and the sadness...
不论是痛苦 还是悲伤 都由我…
No, I refuse!
不要
Even the pains and the sadness is my precious memories.
哪怕是痛苦抑或悲伤 都是我宝贵的回忆
So don't bring them with you.
所以 不要把它们带走
Yes, Masuo. The mud whale is going on a new journey.
对啊玛索 泥鲸的未来就在前方
We need you to continue work hard!
还有的是活等你干呢！
I thought so...
我就知道你们会这么说…
Did you make an appointment?
二位约好了吗？
No, I didn't.
不 没约过
ατσάλι
ατσάλι
You are going to visit Atsali, who is a great commander.
去会见阿查理长官那种级别的要人
It's better to...
怎么能这么突然…
If I made an appointment with him, he might run away from me.
要是跟他约好了 恐怕就会被他逃掉
It's better to go surprisingly.
还不如突然袭击
What happened?
怎么了？
Whew...
哎呀哎呀
It seems that I was so disliked.
看来我还真是惹人讨厌呢
♪　からっぽの靴　からから鳴った
♪　からっぽの靴　からから鳴った
An empty shoe sounds empty
♪　空洞洞的鞋子　喀拉喀拉不停响
♪　からっぽの帽子　あなぼこだらけ
♪　からっぽの帽子　あなぼこだらけ
An empty hat full of holes
♪　空洞洞的帽子　凹凹凸凸变了样
♪　空から目玉が降ってくる
♪　空から目玉が降ってくる
An eye drops from the sky
♪　眼珠子从天而降
♪　からっぽ　からっぽ　なんにもない…
♪　からっぽ　からっぽ　なんにもない…
Empty, empty, everything's empty...
♪　空洞洞　空洞洞　一片精光
Dodge it! You were able to do so, right?
你倒是躲啊 又不是躲不开
The driver died, I ask your help.
车夫死了 拜托你来驾车
ατσάλι
ατσάλι
These guy are sent by Atsali, right?
这些是阿查理的人吧
Yeah, but he is not that serious.
嗯 但是他也不是想置我于死地
It should be a warning only.
大概算是个警告吧
όρκα
όρκα
Orca-sama~
奥尔卡先生
I hurt your beautiful hair.
您美丽的秀发
Sorry for my miss.
刚才瞄偏了 真是对不起
What's wrong with you?
你这是怎么了？
όρκα
όρκα
Cuz Orca-sama is the only one I can rely on.
要是不依靠奥尔卡大人
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Or I can't get back to Fallaina!
我又能怎样才能回到法莱那去
I wanna be there now, I wanna kill them one by one carefully!
现在就想回去 把他们一个个用心地破坏掉
I wanna mess them up cautiously!
把他们视作珍宝 搞得乱七八糟
I wonder... if I was left in that island...
我啊…我的魂魄大概丢在那座岛上了
I am empty now, I can't even make a sound.
如今的我 空洞洞的发不出一点声音
Excuse me, I'm here without an appointment.
抱歉 我不请自来
Did you become hating me?
长官对在下似乎挺满意的
Who is that guy?
那个人是？
She is my record clerk.
我的记录员
It seems that she has her emotions returned.
可她看起来好像感情回复了很多
σάρξ
σάρξ
Yeah, I have given her the sárx.
嗯 因为我给了她「魂肉」
νοῦς
νοῦς
σάρξ
σάρξ
Eating sárx, the meat of Nous vouchsafed by his Majesty according to one's status,
皇帝陛下根据地位赐予的魂形的肉「魂肉」
can avoid one's emotions from being taken by Nous.
通过食用魂肉 可以减少感情被摄取的幅度
Therefore one's mind returns.
心灵也能随之恢复
σάρξ
σάρξ
Only ancestry within the fourth degree of kinship can eat sárx vouchsafed to you.
允许食用魂肉的 应该仅限你的三等亲
Of course I know.
在下当然明白
I know it better than commander.
至少要比长官阁下更清楚
What?
什么？
You and your family
在你家族里
σάρξ
σάρξ
have distributed the sárx to many people
许许多多的人都分到了魂肉这种事情
including your cousins and that person.
包括表亲戚堂亲戚和那个人
We are birds of a feather,
你我是一丘之貉
καρχαρίας
καρχαρίας
why do you want the Karcharías so badly that you even threaten me to get it?
不惜威胁我也要拿到卡鲁哈利阿斯么
I'm not threatening you.
哪里敢威胁阁下
In my case,
就我的行为来说
I can simply marry her.
只要我跟她结下婚姻关系
Then it's legal. That's what I want to mention here.
就不构成犯罪了 还望阁下了解
I don't want kill...
不想杀人…
Please... Please take everything from my mind!
不如… 不如把我的心灵彻底拿走
ατσάλι
ατσάλι
Do you want to be hostile to commander Atsali?
您是打算和阿查理长官为敌么？
Commander will definitely grant our request.
长官一定会接受我们的要求的
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Then we shall go get Fallaina and the Daímonas boy.
在那之后 我们就去缴获法莱那和恶灵少年
νοῦς
άνθρωπος
άνθρωπος
然后从皇帝陛下手中夺取第一魂形「安斯罗珀斯」
In order to create a supreme world.
为了创造至高无上的世界
Are you... joking?
您是在…开玩笑吧？
Rebellion is the most serious crime.
叛逆罪可是最重的罪名
άνθρωπος
άνθρωπος
And you even want the Anthropos...
甚至还想夺取安斯罗帕斯
Yes.
是啊
I will be killed if my scheme get disclosed.
要是阴谋败露 我只有死路一条
Why... are you telling me something so important?
为什么要把这么重要的事情告诉我…？
My destiny is in your hand.
我的命运掌握在你的手上
That is what the wife do.
妻子不就是这种东西么？
Note: Jakko is the land in which Buddha reside.
常寂光土：佛教用语，指佛陀悟道之法身所居的净土
When we are back to the Jakko, our lost paradise,
若有朝一日回归废园的常寂光土
shall we pick up your soul.
我们是否能够拾得你的魂魄
Let the hot sand boil!
热砂哟 翻涌吧
Our hearts are burning forever.
心灵是会永世燃烧的吧
Let the hot sand run!
热砂哟 奔流吧
Our bodies will rise again and again.
我们会一次次站直身体
We will be the eyes and the foots of our warrior.
成为战士的双眼 战士的双脚
Going on a journey together.
一同走过悠远的旅途
Suo-sama!
苏澳哥哥！
We still want Masuo to eat bamboo shoots.
好想让玛索叔叔多吃点竹笋
And drink juice.
还有饮料
Put them all into the coffin.
让我们把它们都放进棺材里吧
He will be hungry in the journey.
旅途遥遥 他总会饿的
Don't cry...
不可以哭的…
I don't!
我不哭…
Don't mind!
…没关系！
Cry out today!
今天只管哭！
Why don't you cry?
你不哭吗？
Isn't he somebody you know well?
死掉的不是你熟人么
Or, you simply can't cry?
还是说 你哭不出来
If you can't cry, then it's fine not to cry.
哭不出来就没办法了 不哭也没关系
Don't mind.
不用在意
It is better to treat it as something not related to us.
不如说事不关己高高挂起还更痛快些
That's what you have done.
你就是这么过来的吧
Perhaps.
或许吧
I forgot.
我早就忘了
It's the first time I saw Oni cry.
我一次都没见欧尼你哭过
I am...
我啊…
A number of records that left by our ancestors,
被祖国放逐的前辈们留下来的 诸多记录
The sand poems written by the previous chiefs.
历代首长们写下的砂词
This is the history of the prisoners on the sea of sand.
这是囚禁在沙海牢狱里的人们 谱写的历史
And it's a sorrowful history of short-lived Shirushi,
这是短命的「印」 和一代代送别他们的「无印」
as well as the Muin who kept send them off.
留下的悲哀的历史
The history of mud whale...
泥鲸的历史…
An oath for the Shirushi of Muin.
为「印」许下的「无印」的誓言
That's what we have written, our history.
是我们亲笔谱写的 我们的历史…
Hey, what's wrong with you?
呐 怎么了？
Why are you so painful?
为什么你会这么痛苦？
Neri?
奈莉？
I think I know your pain a little.
或许你的痛苦 我是能够明白一点的
It's even more painful than being stabbed by a sword.
比被剑贯穿身体
It's even more painful than having drunk the poison.
比饮下毒药
Isn't it?
都要更加难受的吧？
May I help you cancel that pain?
让我来消解你的这份痛苦吧
You will fly from here.
从这里飞翔
Fly higher than the star locusts, and go far away!
比星蝗飞得还要高 还要远！
Then your pain and your misery will go away.
这样 你的痛楚 你的苦恼都会消失得一干二净
You will be free!
你会得到自由
What?
嗯？
It's fine?
不用吗？
I will be here.
我要 留在这里
Oh? Then I won't help you.
是么 那行
It's your own choice.
毕竟这是你的选择
Grandpa Kogare, look!
可加雷爷爷 看啊
This is the mud whale,
这是「泥鲸」
and this is star locust!
这是「星蝗」！
Oh, you have already remembered them.
哟 查克罗都记住这么多了啊
What about the next?
接下来呢？
Teach me the next word, Grandpa Kogare!
快教我下一个字 可加雷爷爷
All right, I will teach you Sunamodori.
那就教你「还沙日」吧
Hey Chakuro,
呐 查克罗
am I strange?
我很奇怪吗？
Huh, why?
诶 哪里奇怪了？
Urumi and Aine told me,
乌露米和艾奈都说我奇怪
I am like a sister to Chakuro.
说是跟查克罗在一起就像兄妹一样
Yeah, you are.
嗯 是呢
I am not! I am not your sister!
哪里是了！ 我们又不是兄妹！
Uh? But I know it.
呃？ 嗯 这我知道
You don't!
你根本不知道！
Huh?
诶？
Huh...
诶…
Ouch!
哇
Chakuro, what do you think about me?
查克罗 你觉得我是个什么样的女孩子？
About you? Eh...
什么样的？ 嗯…
You don't need to tell me, but write it down!
不跟我说也行 好好写下来
Write?
写下来？
Yes!
嗯！
Tell everyone clearly what a girl I am.
让大家清清楚楚明白 我是个什么样的女孩子
So everyone will remember me with your words.
只要读到 就能让大家想起我
That's it... I wanted to tell everyone...
是啊… 我本来是想把我们的故事写给大家的
I wanted everyone to remember...
想让大家一直记住我们…
Sami and Grandpa Kogare, as well as Taisha-sama and Masuo,
不论是莎米还是可加雷爷爷 台霞姐姐或者是玛索
the people died before me,
先我而去的人
the time on the mud whale, the happiness,
泥鲸上度过的时光 快乐的回忆
the reasons of tears, all of them...
泪水的理由 全部全部
That's why I was writing.
所以 我一直在挥笔撰写…
So this is what you have decided.
这就是你的决定么
Yes.
是的
I wonder if Shirushi are able to bear it...
不知道各位「印」能不能够接受得了…
What will you do if they become desperate?
要是他们绝望了 变得自暴自弃了该怎么办
But we can't just stay in the mud whale, accept their short lives,
难道就让他们留在泥鲸 接受自己的短命
and refuse the changes and the future!
拒绝变化与未来吗
We should choose the new world and possibilities!
或者是 去选择新世界和可能性
For me,
是我的话
I don't want to regret when I die.
当我迎来死神之时 我不想留下遗憾
A gather for everybody...
全体集合这种事
It's the first time since the enemies' attack.
从前阵子敌人来袭以后就再也没有了吧？
Don't say there's another...
难不成 又来了？
I'm scared!
好害怕啊
What I can do now, is to keep the truth.
如今的我能做到的 是记录真实！
Suo.
苏澳
It's about to go, are you fine?
差不多到时间了 能行吗？
You need consciousness and responsibility as a leader.
为人君者 必须要有觉悟和责任
You can't lead people without being ready to have them.
没有觉悟的话是当不了的
Yes.
…是的
I will tell...
我要写给大家…
The anxiety, the fear, and the incredulity...
不安 恐怖 怀疑…
They are...
这是…
our strong desire to live.
想要求生的强烈希望…
I want to record the lives of this ship and the people on this ship.
我要把这艘船和船上的人民的 生命的记录留给大家
I am the Chief Suo.
我是首长苏澳
Thank you for your gathering.
感谢各位能够汇聚一堂
Today, as a Muin,
今天 作为「无印」的一员
I have to tell something to every Shirushi.
我有话一定要跟各位「印」讲
Since I was a child,
自年幼之时
I feel sad about Shirushi's short lives,
我就对「印」的各位英年早逝这件事
your fate of dying young.
感到无比的悲伤
Muin can live tens of years,
明明「无印」可以度过数十年的岁月
but why Shirushi can't?
为什么「印」却不能呢
I always think it's unreasonable and not fair.
这一直让我感到无法容忍 觉得不合情理
Oni!
欧尼！
Captain...
…是团长啊…
Are you looking for him?
你在找他么？
I can't find him everywhere.
到处都找不到
We are gathering for Suo's speech...
明明大家都要集合去听苏澳的讲话的
The chief's speech, OK.
首长的讲话 啊
Huh?
诶？
Oni is different from you.
欧尼和你们不同
Don't you know?
你知道么
Oni is...
欧尼他
He will never keep company with anybody.
跟谁都不会混在一起
One day he will leave you.
总有一天他一定会离你们而去
You don't even know Oni well!
你明明一点也不了解欧尼！
Why can you say...
凭什么能说出这种…
It's my advise.
这是我的忠告
Oni!
欧尼！
She is our fellow.
这家伙是我们的伙伴
I don't cry.
我不哭
But I also don't forget them!
但这并不代表我会忘却！
Then you shall go.
那你们去吧
Kicha, let's go.
绮茶 我们走
Ya, yeah.
嗯 嗯…
You don't cry...
「我不哭」么…
The mud whale is eating our lives?
原来泥鲸在吞噬我们的生命吗
Then what the Muin are!
那「无印」到底算什么！
My child might have a longer life...
我孩子本来也能多活几年的么？
In other words, Muin are depriving our lives!
也就是说那帮「无印」夺去了我们的生命！
Those old guys are sacrificing us to keep them on the sea!
这帮老朽为了自己不沉入海底
They are not just drags for us,
要只是碍手碍脚倒也算了
but they are also robbing us!
这帮家伙根本就是强盗！
No, they are killing us!
不 是杀人犯！
Stop it!
住手！
Suocchi!
苏澳澳！
What have you done! You coward!
你们在做什么啊！ 卑鄙下流！
Are you standing on Muin's side as a Shirushi?
明明自己是「印」 还要站在「无印」那边么
If we are coward, then you are a traitor!
我们卑鄙下流的话 你就是叛徒！
A lot of Shirushi died in the previous war.
前段时间的战争里 许许多多的「印」死去了
Do you mean they were deceived by the Muin,
难道你们说他们是被「无印」所欺骗
and their deaths are wasted?
白白送死的吗！
Those who died...
死去的那些人…
Nibi, Aijiro, Buki,
不论尼比 艾吉洛 布奇…
and many others,
还是其他许许多多的人
they fought and died for everybody here in the mud whale!
大家都是为了全体泥鲸人民英勇牺牲的
It has nothing to do with Shirushi or Muin.
跟「印」还是「无印」没关系
Even they will never know the truth.
哪怕不知道真实
I will never forget they were living here!
我也绝对不会忘记 和他们生活的点点滴滴！
Please understand.
请各位理解
Our ancestors were not keeping silence for their own peace.
我们的前辈并非为了自己的安宁而选择沉没
Muin never want you short-lived Shirushi to live with fear and sympathy.
「无印」从来都不曾希望
We want you to enjoy splendid short lives!
我们希望「印」能够讴歌自己短暂而灿烂的人生
Of course Taisha-sama and Hakuji-sama also wanted.
不论是台霞姐姐 还是哈库奇爷爷 都是如此…
All the Muin wants that.
所有的「无印」都怀着这样的希冀
That is the Cage of Fallaina!
这就是「法莱那的牢笼」么！
We must get out here soon, it's dangerous!
不赶紧突破这里的话会很危险的！
There are still creatures here!
在这里还有生物！
Ouch, Ham?
哇 哈姆？
κόκαλο
κόκαλο
Kókkalo!
骨头！
Ah, wait!
啊 等等！
Neri!
奈莉
Neri, are you looking?
奈莉 你看到了吗？
Ah...
啊…
Are you OK?
你没事吧？
Huh? Ah...
呃？ 啊…
I'm sorry.
对不起
Huh?
咦？
Why did Lykos apologize?
为什么黎可斯要道歉？
Don't you hate me?
你不恨我吗？
Of course no!
哪里有！
Eh, I was surprised when I heard your words.
不… 刚听到黎可斯的话的时候 我很惊讶
I felt uncomfortable.
感觉自己不能接受
Sami and Nibi,
莎米和尼比
as well as Musuo, I feel sorry for every Shirushi's death.
还有玛索和其他「印」的死去让我悲伤
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But we can't blame Fallaina for all of them.
但是 这不全是法莱那的错
From now on, I will share all the truths with everyone.
从现在开始 我将与各位共享所有的真实
Now we have the rudder, we can decide where we are going.
在得到舵 能够决定船的前进方向的今天
It's time for us to find new friends.
我们迎来了寻找新的伙伴的时机
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Together with Fallaina,
我们将与法莱那一同
let's aiming to the new word, the land of freedom!
向着新的世界 自由的大地进发！
Translator
翻
ssnake
译
♪　私たちを
ssnake
Please find us
翻
♪　見つけておくれ
♪　見つけておくれ
in the sea of sand
♪　请把我们找到
Timing
时 间 轴
zwc1991
zwc1991
♪　泥の舟で櫂を漕ぎ
♪　泥の舟で櫂を漕ぎ
Rowing the paddles of the mud ship
♪　让泥船儿荡起双桨
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
Sleeping in the white sand
♪　夜晚以白沙为床
♪　小さな旅人よ
♪　小さな旅人よ
Oh, the little traveler
♪　小小的旅行者啊
♪　千重の時間の中
♪　千重の時間の中
Though we will finally meet each other
♪　在万千时光之中
♪　必ず出会うけれど
♪　必ず出会うけれど
after a long long time
♪　我们终会相会
Oni.
欧尼
♪　蝶の落涙のように
♪　蝶の落涙のように
But just like the tears of a butterfly
♪　但却像蝴蝶零落的泪珠
Let's make friends when we arrive at Amonlogia!
到了阿蒙洛基亚 让我们一起去寻找新的伙伴吧
It doesn't matter
不论生在何方
♪　二度と触れられない
♪　二度と触れられない
we will no longer reach each other again
♪　再也不能触及彼此
where you were born, or what power you have,
不论拥有什么力量 都没有关系
if we have strong friendships and deep bonds.
只要我们有着坚实而深厚的友谊
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
Even we want be together
♪　哪怕想要与你化为一体
And I want you
另外 希望你能
to be the leader of our new community.
成为新社群的领袖
I want you to be the pivot of everybody's heart.
成为各位心灵的中枢
If you are not confident, you'd better refuse it as soon as possible.
要是没有自信的话 不如早点拒绝
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
we will be apart forever
♪　也只能散落成无限的飞沙
Roharito-sama, you are too straight!
罗哈里特大人 话说得太直白了
Oni will surely become popular among us.
欧尼一定会很有人望的
What?
什么？
What did you say? I can't stand it!
你说啥！ 这我可不能充耳不闻！
It's a pinch for Roharito-sama!
您遇到劲敌了 罗哈里特大人
What?
嗯？
♪　私たちを
♪　私たちを
Please find us
♪　茫茫沙海中
This is our new ship.
这就是我们的新船
How wonderful it is!
不错吧
♪　見つけておくれ
♪　見つけておくれ
in the sea of sand
♪　请把我们找到
Everywhere is empty.
到处都是空洞洞的
We will soon depart!
我们马上就要启程
♪　泥の舟で櫂を漕ぎ
♪　泥の舟で櫂を漕ぎ
Rowing the paddles of the mud ship
♪　让泥船儿荡起双桨
All for the empire!
一切都是「为了帝国」！
If you can meet...
妹妹…
What?
嗯？
I hope you can meet your younger sister.
要是能见到妹妹就好了
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
Sleeping in the white sand
♪　夜晚以白沙为床
♪　小さな旅人よ
♪　小さな旅人よ
Oh, the little traveler
♪　小小的旅行者啊
Mama, you must felt.
妈妈 你感觉到了吗
♪　小さな旅人よ
♪　小さな旅人よ
Oh, the little traveler
♪　小小的旅行者啊
We are going on a journey.
要出发了呢 我们
I want...
我啊…
Eh?
诶？
Even I will have to shorten my life,
哪怕削减自己的生命…
even I will have to abandon my hometown,
哪怕抛弃自己的故乡…
I want to live here, with Chakuro and your fellows.
也希望能跟查克罗你们 一起生活在这里
Yeah.
…嗯
We are living in the mud whale, we are the children of the mud whale.
我们是和泥鲸共同生存的 泥鲸的孩子
It is great I was born here.
能生在这里真是太好了
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
It is great I can live with us.
不论命运  还是感情  亲爱的孩子们哟
And even in the future...
在我们的未来 也要永远…
Towards the future, go ahead
向着未来  向着前方
さ  き
さ  き
その先へ　その未来へ
その先へ　その未来へ
If you can be our guide
導かれたのなら
導かれたのなら
只要有你指引前路
The mud whale had crossed the torrent called the cage of Fallaina,
泥鲸穿过名为「法莱那的牢笼」的激流
Thousands of words, leaving for the fantasy lands
幾千の声　空想の地へ
幾千の声　空想の地へ
万千寄语  向着空想的彼岸
and was heading to Amonlogia.
开始向着阿蒙洛基亚进发
Steering towards the opposite
舵を切って行こうとした
舵を切って行こうとした
相信信念调转方向
It was August 16, 93 S.S.
这是砂刑历93年
Thousands of songs, they are the ballads of the sea of sand
バラード
バラード
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
万千欢声  是沙海的歌谣
Our journey will continue.
旅途——